<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sabrina Peters</title>
    <description>I&#39;m a MLIS student, librarian-in-training, and aspiring agitator for good.</description>
    <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://sabrinapeters.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reasons that include life, I have been without my own laptop for almost six months, and my main access to the interwebs has been through mobile devices. That greatly discouraged me from posting anything on here, and I also used the excuse of working full-time to deter me from really writing anything at all. Then, my site went down, got fixed, went down again, then got &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/2920760-Sabrina-s-Blog&quot;&gt;prettied up&lt;/a&gt; and fixed again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also, for other reasons I may discuss later, I believe I have been experiencing a mild depression due to chemical imbalance, caused by a variety of factors. )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I have a pretty site (except for some copyediting, maybe), and a working laptop (which Charles helped me set up). We finished setting up the laptop late last night, after I got home from work. I went to bed feeling super excited to write with an actual keyboard and a screen in front of me, and not have angry thumbs from typing on my phone so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I wake up this morning feeling like I had run a half-marathon in my sleep (no, I don’t actually know what that feels like - just guessing). I stay in bed until a little bit past 10 o’clock, feeling guilty about being in bed, even though it’s my Saturday. I feel too tired to even think about writing until I have a very strong cup of of PG Tips, then I begin to reflect on why I felt guilty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core reason: somehow, waking up and getting up early feels more righteous (I know, total [sorry, Mom] bullshit) than sleeping late. Why, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I want to blame Christian fundamentalism. I heard all my life, in one way or another, until I graduated college, that mornings were the most appropriate time for “quiet time”. (At one point, I was even told it was a sin if I hit the snooze button.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is this general common perception that anyone who doesn’t wake up early is somehow lazy. Naturally, I wonder how that came to be the perception. I surmise that it has to do with work that needs to be completed while it’s daylight. I imagine that before electricity was used, getting up with the sun ensured that there was enough light to complete a day’s work. We have electricity now, so getting up early isn’t as necessary; however, sleeping in is still perceived as laziness, more often than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I conclude that what’s behind my guilty feeling is a combination of cultural perception and Christian fundamentalism, but that does not make the feeling go away. Sigh. I decide to get up and bake some hash browns, even though it’s past noon at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I am not alone in this feeling of guilt, so tell me what you think. Do you feel guilty about not waking up before a certain point? Why?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2016/08/28/welcome-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2016/08/28/welcome-back/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>British TV</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/broadchurch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alec Hardy and Ellie Miller on the beach&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;via The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got hooked on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2357547/&quot;&gt;Jessica Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; over break, after I rewatched &lt;em&gt;Sherlock (BBC)&lt;/em&gt; for the fourth time. After I finished watching it, I scrolled through Netflix’s British TV recommendations, and noticed &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2249364/&quot;&gt;Broadchurch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (probably because of the David Tennant connection!). I thought, Eh, why not, and pretty much couldn’t quit until I finished. I’m a sucker for a good story; once immersed into the plot, through page or screen, I have trouble reemerging until its conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed lately that British television has been a lot more appealing to me than American television, so I started to make a list of reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: I don’t pretend to be a screen critic, so this is not very explicative by any means. Even pretending to be a critic would mean ditching life as I currently know it, in order to watch and rewatch films and shows so I could write about them, and who would want that? [Who am I kidding - that sounds awesome!])&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my list, in no particular order, with a few short explanations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;em&gt;Pride &amp;amp; Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; (the Colin Firth version, duh)&lt;br /&gt;
2) &lt;em&gt;Broadchurch&lt;/em&gt; (I almost got emotional at the end of season two, because the tone of redemption was so strong.)&lt;br /&gt;
3) &lt;em&gt;Sherlock&lt;/em&gt; (did you catch the New Year’s special? That was a fun ride, and brilliantly done. Simply brilliant.)&lt;br /&gt;
4) &lt;em&gt;Downton Abbey&lt;/em&gt; (This is basically a light soap opera, but that doesn’t stop me from watching!)&lt;br /&gt;
5) &lt;em&gt;Doc Martin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
6) &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt; (I will acknowledge this is great television, but I hate feeling so existential when I watch it.)&lt;br /&gt;
7) Rich character development - this has been especially noticeable in &lt;em&gt;Broadchurch&lt;/em&gt;, since it was a crucial part of the story.&lt;br /&gt;
8) The actors in British television seem more realistic to me. American television tends to use actors that are above average in looks, and many times on the thin side. Actors don’t need to look like models.&lt;br /&gt;
9) Scenic settings - I think this mostly refers to &lt;em&gt;Doc Martin&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Broadchurch&lt;/em&gt;. Who wouldn’t want to be living in a little British seaside town?&lt;br /&gt;
10) Vocabulary - this is kind of a silly thing to note, but I like that British has a wider variety of slang. I get tired of hearing the same American idioms (and curse words).&lt;br /&gt;
11) Dry humor - c.f. &lt;em&gt;Sherlock&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2016/01/13/british-tv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2016/01/13/british-tv/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Out with the Old</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve published on here, if you’re not counting my class project. A lot of things have happened since I last posted any kind of reflection. I figured it was time for a good ol’ update before 2015 completely ran out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant happenings, in short: we moved cross-country in the middle of August, my brother got married in October, and my attention went toward fall quarter classwork&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some less significant happenings: I had my first taste of strong, boozy eggnog. I also managed not to mess up a whole roasted chicken recipe, and made bone broth from its remains. I’m still doing yoga, some weeks less than others. I’ve assembled some shelves, and might’ve awakened an inner pyromaniac by burning candles, and attempting to start fires in the wood stove. I LOVE a good fire. Oh, and I’ve become even more obsessed with houseplants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advent was hard, and I caught myself crying to Robbie Seay music instead of singing along. Christmastide has ushered in a feeling of optimism, and I think 2016 is going to be a very good year. I can think of several reasons why, at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) I’ve made some New Year’s resolutions. I’m not usually one for resolutions, because, let’s be honest, I’m not good at keeping them. I hope to set forth some personal goals 2016 that will continue into the following years. Some are: eat more (Seriously! There are multiple reasons why I don’t eat enough, and I feel it. I don’t feel healthy and strong.), increase cardiovascular fitness (yoga isn’t doing it, so I’m going to start walking/running again), be forthcoming about my boundaries, curse out loud at least twice per month (I think this is a separate blog post!), and establish daily structure (husband and I have already started one ritual: 6:45am coffee and tea, complete with a teapot, a French press, and matching cups and saucers all on a tray - it’s really a lovely, quiet time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) We’re not moving across states! We moved twice this year: from Lynchburg to Lewistown, and from Lewistown to Tacoma. Moving out of town is a soul-sucker, and I’m really glad we’re not moving for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Job hunting has not been successful this year, so I’m going to devote some time to volunteering (which I should’ve been doing, anyhow), and writing more. I think having a writing buddy would help motivate me, so if you want one, too, hit me up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Related to my health goals, I’m in the process of connecting with a nutritionist, in order to narrow down some of my food sensitivities, that are related to what my current doctor is treating as IBS. No more guessing what I can or cannot eat! (This is, of course, assuming that I find an awesome nutritionist right away, and don’t have to spend my time shopping for one.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) I’ve let go of my legalistic impulses in regard to having a strict, regimented scripture reading and praying time. That is, I’m not going to beat myself up if I miss a day or three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) I’ve started getting regular, professional massages. They are wonderfully relaxing. Friends, if you don’t mind physical touch, and can handle any possible side effects from a massage, get them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) I’ve started to (slowly) learn Python. I’m not sure how I’ll be using it specifically, but it’s a good skill to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) This last in the list, but I don’t think it’s least. We’ll be getting a new mattress within the next week! Sleeping has been a chore more nights than not, complete with various aches and pains. I’m excited to be able to sleep well and wake up feeling good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s got you excited for 2016?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/12/31/out/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/12/31/out/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Class Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, here I am after the summer and most of autumn, with a new blog post! It’s not my usual fare, but rather a repository for what I’m sure will be the first of several school projects. So, if you like to listen to me talk, take a gander at my presentation. If you’d like to learn about my workshop in more depth, take a look at the accompanying documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re my peer reviewer: hi! Welcome to my site. For the purpose of this assignment, I thought it would be easier just to insert a blog post on my existing site, rather than create another separate repository.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for a project in LIS 560: Instructional and Training Strategies for Information Professionals. My assignment was to choose a user group, learn about its characteristics, information needs and information seeking behaviors, and then design a workshop teaching skills to meet one or more of the needs. Please find below a) my presentation overview, b) a brief literature review of the user group, c) the lesson plan, and d) a workshop rubric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/YJMMQs1vT44&quot;&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/exjdf1xqlts5522/Peters_TrainingModA.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;Training Module Part A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/y5jmox1g80xg0wt/Peters_TrainingModB.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;Training Module Part B: Lesson Plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xgr2l7qbu4jky55/TrainingModRubric.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;Student Rubric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/11/29/class-project-one/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/11/29/class-project-one/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Loneliness, Love, and the Church</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since June 26th, there have been countless articles, social media statuses, and blog posts from one end of the spectrum to the other, both inside the universal church and outside of it. I don’t have any new arguments to offer. I have tried to do my best to listen to the arguments I’ve heard since I was young, that have been recycled numerous times over, and are frankly getting old. I am also trying my best to listen to the arguments with which I am not as familiar, and present a different viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t wish to address the debates outside the Church, because what concerns me is how those inside the Church, which is supposed to be a conduit of Christ’s love, are handling this issue, an issue that concerns real people, with flesh, blood, heart, and soul. Actually, I don’t want to insert myself into any debates, at all. And let me say, it’s been disappointing to see that so many conservative Christians cannot accept the fact that other Christians can be just as devout, while holding to differing interpretations of scripture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen so many Christians dismiss LGBTQ folks, not necessarily with just their words, but with their attitudes. Discussing LGBTQ issues as though they are merely topics for a debate, and not people, really emphasizes the whole “speak the truth…” thing, but the “…in love” aspect is abandoned when, well, the focus is on “issues” . Do you really think you’re going to convince someone by winning a debate? Are you really “speaking the truth in love” by talking over and around someone? Is that kind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prominent argument for marriage equality that I’ve seen, from Christians, starts with the problem of loneliness, taken from beginning chapters of Genesis. Adam is lonely, so God gives him Eve, because it isn’t good for man to be alone. Right? But what happens for someone who is not heterosexual, and who desires a lifelong companion, when marriage is strictly defined as between a man and a woman? They’re left to cope with being lonely for a lifetime, and loneliness…well, loneliness is a terrible feeling most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I think mostly everyone can agree that loneliness is a legitimate state of being, and that, in general, love and companionship are very good things. Lifetime companionship is very good. Humans need love and companionship. All humans do. Yes? Yes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In almost every conservative, Evangelical church I’ve attended, lifetime love and companionship (read: marriage) have been held to such a high degree of esteem, that any group of single folks weren’t actually Singles, but People Who Aren’t Married Yet, and thus a problem to be fixed. Celibacy? We don’t talk about it, except to communicate that sex is bad until marriage. Loneliness? There’s nothing like hanging out with a group of married people from church to amplify any faint feelings of loneliness, but don’t talk about it. Just get those single people married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those churches, marriage is so highly desirable that it is perhaps even a step toward a higher form of Christianity, because it is this wonderful, glorious, romantic, but hard road of sanctification (because who better reveals your faults other than someone who is close to you?) and companionship, and guess what, it even reflects Christ and his bride, the Church!  Why would anyone NOT want that? Why would anyone NOT want to have their identity based upon, eventually, being tied to someone else for life? Forget loneliness; that doesn’t need to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see a problem? I do. I am concerned that many churches’ histories of treating single folks as issues leaves it vastly incompetent to address issues of celibacy and loneliness for anyone, let alone LGBTQ folks, and has not communicated love or kindness in this area. When a church can’t even deal with heterosexual singles as simply wonderfully created individuals, and not just deficient, Not Married Yets, how can a LGBTQ person, Christian or not, expect to find a loving community as a single person?  Because a church has beaten them over the head saying they cannot marry someone of their own choosing, while proclaiming marriage as the highest good (um, have you forgotten about St. Paul?), how could they not feel inadequate? How could they NOT feel unwelcome? And how does this help the problem of loneliness? It sure as hell doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing Christ’s love to another person means reaching beyond the issues, and embracing their humanity. This goes for every self-proclaimed follower of Christ, regardless of where you are on the theological spectrum. Even though our efforts are imperfect, we try. And when we have failed, we confess, ask for forgiveness, ask how we can do better, and then try again. We ask for grace to go forth in love and kindness. The problem is when we have not stopped to ask if we can do better, so let me say that if you are not asking how your church is loving people who have been historically dismissed, othered, and deeply hurt, then something is definitely wrong. I don’t care what your theology is, and I don’t think we need to sit around and debate hermeneutics. If people are just seen as their “issue”, they will not want to stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confess, ask how we can do better, and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go forth in love and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/15/june-26/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/15/june-26/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Tuesday Morning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As Anne Lamott says, “butt in chair.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I don’t have any brilliant ideas, but need to practice writing (last week’s post sorely reminded me that I’ve gotten really rusty!), here is a chronicle of my morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:25 First alarm rings, playing the intro to Almighty God (Bonus Track). Bleary eyed, I turn it off and set a new alarm for 30 minutes later. I had stayed up until past midnight, watching the newest episode of True Detective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:55, second alarm rings, as well as Charlie’s. I take my phone and quickly scroll through Twitter. Then I get out of bed, brush my hair and tie it back, get dressed (t-shirt and basketball shorts), clean and put on my glasses, and head out of the bedroom into the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:04 I decide to oil-pull, so I pour (it’s summer, which means the coconut oil is liquid!) 2 tablespoons of coconut oil into a tiny medicine measuring cup, and toss it into my mouth. I need to swish it around for 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:04 I fill up the water bottles (one is mine, one is C’s) that are on the kitchen counter, put C’s in the refrigerator, and grab my morning supplements (L-Tyrosine) from the hall closet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:06 I take my water bottle and supplements to the living room, where I sit on the couch, browsing Twitter on my phone, until the 20 minutes of oil-pulling are up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:24 I spit out the coconut oil, and rinse out my mouth with warm water. Then I take my supplements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:25 I sit back on the couch, and read the Daily Lectionary scriptures on my iPad, using the ESV Bible app. I am not really partial to the ESV, but aesthetically speaking, it’s got the best Bible app around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(From here on out my times are estimates, which is why they’re so even.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 8:45, Charlie emerges and asks for breakfast. I go back to the kitchen, fry up 10 pieces of uncured bacon on the cast iron griddle, and pour the grease into a mason jar. Then I scramble two eggs with some salt, pepper, and a bit of leftover bacon grease. I work on drinking water while I make breakfast. After I’m done I let C know it’s ready. He is situated in his home office, and requests his breakfast there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:05 I finally finish cleaning up the griddle after breakfast (I love the griddle, but it’s annoying to use for two reasons: 1. It’s heavy, 2. It must be cleaned directly after use), and decide to wipe down the dining table. I take the table runner and throw it in the washer along with various kitchen towels and placemats. Then I notice that the floor under the table needs to be swept, so I sweep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:20 I sit back down on the couch to enjoy my cup of green tea. (I have this morning eating and drinking routine that I follow: water, tea [or coffee if I’m on a coffee kick!], then breakfast. I can usually follow this routine fairly consistently because C isn’t always up in the morning. But, regardless of whether or not I cook breakfast for the both of us, I can never manage to sit down to my breakfast until between 10 and 11.) I contemplate doing yoga before breakfast, but skip it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:30 I get lost on social media, but I do find a FB event that is scheduled for tonight in the Seattle area. It is a Black Lives Matter Solidarity March, and I know some people who could potentially participate. I share the event. My friend Beth tweets that she is looking for things to do in Seattle today, so I try to help by suggesting the Central Library, Pike’s Place, UW Suzzallo, Kubota Garden, Underground Tours, and Space Needle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 10:15 C comes into the living room to give me a hug, because he (we are) is excited about applying to a rental house we found in Tacoma last night. We joke around for a while, and notice my stomach growling. I remember that I need to eat breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:20 I make a three-egg-white omelet with spinach and some parmesan, because that is how many eggs are left in the carton, and I don’t want to dig out the new carton of eggs. I take a peach out of the refrigerator, and cut a slice to taste test it. I decide to have that with my omelet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:30 I set down my breakfast on the table. I remember that I didn’t actually get the washing machine going, so I go back to the laundry room to fix it. C calls me from the office. I find out he needs the Comcast password, which I have forgotten. So I sit down with my iPad to retrieve the password, and type it into his computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:40 I eat breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:50 I decide to take out the kitchen trash. I notice there are maggots in the outside garbage can, again. I remember to take out the wet contents of the washer. I put the towels in the dryer, and lay out the table runner and placemats to dry. I also take a phone call. It is the hospital, reminding me about my procedure tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:00 Back on the couch, I take out my laptop to look at my brother’s resume, for which he had requested some editing help. The file format is RTF, so instead of experimenting with Apple Pages, I use Google Docs to make some tweaks and offer suggestions with the comments feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:15 I decide to write this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:30 C asks me to check the mail. I think he is expecting something, because it is probably too early for the mail. While I’m out on the porch, I notice the jade is looking dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:35 I water the jade, and as I’m wondering about the hanging plants, C says we’re going to my FIL’s house across the street to use his printer. We need to print out the rental application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:40 The printer isn’t working. We decide to go another route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:45 I come back to my laptop, and continue to work on this self-assigned writing practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/07/morning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/07/morning/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I (Don&#39;t) Pledge Allegiance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;photo by Beverly &amp;amp; Pack, via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/walkadog/3366563115&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tatteredflag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tattered flag&quot; title=&quot;Patriotic Waving Tattered Shredding American Flag, Old Glory, The Red White and Blue, Stars &amp;amp; Stripes, That Ragged Old Flag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I pledge allegiance to the flag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;of the United States of America, and to the republic for which it stands,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;one nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about this for the past year (maybe longer), and have decided that I can no longer recite the Pledge of Allegiance in good conscience. I can’t pledge my loyalty a flag, or the nation it represents, because I am not loyal to the United States of America. I’ll give some historical, contextual reasons, and some theological reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: Please do not read this as a defense for my position. This is simply my reflection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historical&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The USA is not one nation under God, despite what some believe. “One nation under God” was not added to the pledge until 1954, and if you do a quick Google search, you can check out the history behind it. The USA has never been a Christian nation. The right to bear arms, the right to free speech, and the right to individual liberty, are not inherently Christian principles. The founding fathers were not all Christians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about the context surrounding the Declaration of Independence and ask myself, who wrote and signed it? Who did they have in mind when they signed onto this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was the revolution instigated? How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me say first and foremost that I am not a historian by any means, so if you want a nice, succinct summary of some of the problems surrounding the first Independence Day, read &lt;a href=&quot;http://universityabbey.org/blog/seventh-annual-debunking-the-fourth/&quot;&gt;Carson’s annual blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I’ve been slowly making my way through Howard Zinn’s &lt;em&gt;A People’s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt;. If I’ve been understanding his interpretation correctly, he asserts that the Revolutionary War was instigated, at least in part, because some of the upper class did not want to answer to the British government for their unjust treatment of poor tenants, who were working the rich guys’ land. The instigators were then able to stir up discontent amongst lower classes in order to gain bodies for the cause. If this is in fact true, then the origins of Revolutionary War and the following Declaration of Independence remain dubious to me. I am extremely hesitant to say that the Revolutionary War was justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about who wrote the Declaration of Independence, and who signed onto it, it’s clear they did not have liberty and justice in mind for everyone. These were upper and middle class men. The upper class, who owned land and property, could still treat the poor however they wanted; women were not seen as equals (they were more seen as, dare I say, property), the first settlers used and slaughtered the indigenous people because they were “savages”, and…not to mention the slave trade. Liberty and justice for all? Liberty and justice for middle to upper class white men, yes. But, everyone? I think not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For more on the meaning of liberty for all, read Frederick Douglass’ 1852 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lib.rochester.edu/index.cfm?PAGE=2945&quot;&gt;speech on the Fourth of the July&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theological&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last week, these gospel verses were in the lectionary readings. I am more familiar with Matthew’s account, so I never really paid attention to the way Luke recounts this scene in chapter 22. The way Jesus replies, “No more of this!” had me thinking the entire week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When those who were around him saw what was coming, they asked, “Lord, should we strike with the sword?” Then one of them struck the slave of the high priest and cut off his right ear.  But Jesus said, “No more of this!” And he touched his ear and healed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s Matthew’s version, for comparison, from chapter 26:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then they came and laid hands on Jesus and arrested him. Suddenly, one of those with Jesus put his hand on his sword, drew it, and struck the slave of the high priest, cutting off his ear. Then Jesus said to him, “Put your sword back into its place; for all who take the sword will perish by the sword. Do you think that I cannot appeal to my Father, and he will at once send me more than twelve legions of angels?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have all the details worked out, but it’s safe to say I have pacifist convictions, which is why I have cited those scriptures as an example of reliance on something (Someone, in this case) other than weapons. That would mean, naturally, that I wouldn’t have approved of the Revolutionary War in the first place, let alone for political reasons. (Although, being a woman, they wouldn’t have taken me seriously, which renders my opinion completely irrelevant!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any Christian who is familiar with the scriptures can tell you that there is teaching about our citizenship as disciples of Jesus (see the Letter to the Philippians, for example). That is, our actual citizenship doesn’t belong to any earthly nation. Sure, my passport declares my U.S. citizenship, but it’s not what counts. God’s going to make a new earth, and Jesus will be (is) King. The United States, however, is hanging by a thread. Why would I pledge allegiance that nation? Why should I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I am grateful to live here. I’m comfortable here. I’m happy to be able to freely exchange ideas, and to interact with so many diverse people. But, why would I pledge my loyalty to any nation that lives in constant fear, because was founded in violence and subjugation, and is therefore reliant upon military power? This does not seem like true liberty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t need to pledge allegiance to any nation, so I’m not going to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I choose to pledge allegiance to King Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/02/i-pledge-allegiance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/07/02/i-pledge-allegiance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Survivor&#39;s Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you haven’t seen the prologue to this piece, go &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sabrinapeters.net/2015/05/27/dear-self-shut-up/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Church should be a safe and nurturing place for those who have been deeply hurt by acts of violence, more often than not, it is exactly the opposite. Victims experience shame and fear, but do not feel safe enough to come forward; in cases like this one below, victims are only made to feel &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; shame in the church. One key to creating a safe space is an openness and willingness to listen, which is why I would like you to read and consider one survivor’s story, instead of insisting that they should be ready to forgive and reconcile at all costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Anonymous&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I felt shame. I was in middle school and my youth pastor was talking about sex (and sexual contact) before marriage. During his talk, he went on and on about how wrong it was, and how God blesses the marriage of those who wait, and how sex before marriage was not only a sin against God, but against your own body and that of your future spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart was beating loudly and I was trying not to look at anyone as most of the kids around me began to sing the closing song of our youth service. I spent the rest of the day praying for God to forgive me. I was sure I was dirty. I was sure no one would ever love me. I was sure that I was beyond repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, since I was 8 years old my step brother had been sexually abusing me. The abuse lasted until I was 14, when he was caught with illegal drugs and with a weapon in school and sent away to juvenile detention. I have not seen him since (he moved several states away with his mother after getting out of detention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I still had my shame and I was determined no one was going to know about it. Don’t get me wrong, I had a mom who taught me sexual education and who told me many times that no one should touch me without my permission. I was not raised in a Quiverfull household. Our family was mostly Christian in name only–you know, the shine-yourself-up on Sunday and get drunk Monday night kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I had a church who heaped shame on sex before marriage. That same pastor, and others throughout my life preached several messages on how important it was to be a virgin on your wedding night and what an awesome gift that would be to give to your husband. A gift I could never give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also remember a vivid conversation with my Aunt, who was my favorite person in all the world. One summer when I was visiting and about 10, she forbade me to play with a little girl who lived next door with her grandparents. When I asked about it, she replied that this girl was sexually abused by her father. She wouldn’t let this little girl play with me because, she said, girls and boys who are abused usually abuse others, and she didn’t want me around her. I buried my abuse deeper at that point. I never wanted to be someone who my Aunt thought capable of abuse. I didn’t want to be sent away. I wanted to be a good girl and be blessed by God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m older I know words such as “modesty culture” and “body shaming” both things that my church participated in. I didn’t know those words then. I just knew I both hated and loved my body and the attention it afforded me. I know that I thought of my body as not my own. I thought it belonged to my future husband. I thought I didn’t have a right to say no because I was already tainted by my past. I thought I should like it when boys touched me, I should be honored that they even paid attention to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought my past into many dating relationships and it took getting married to finally stop and deal with everything that had happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love going to church now. I attend a church that, while talking about God’s plan for marriage and for our bodies, does so in a way that does not shame. And while my church isn’t perfect, I feel welcomed and also completely comfortable with asking questions and exploring doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what the world needs. But I do think it needs less body shaming and less twisted scripture used as a control point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I do wish more people talked about the rights of victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know now that God sees me as pure and holy before Him. And I know that when I did meet the man that I now call my husband—there was absolutely nothing lacking on our wedding night, except for perhaps more chocolate covered strawberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More survivor stories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boz.religionnews.com/2015/05/28/sexually-assaulted-in-a-christian-home-a-victim-speaks/&quot;&gt;Rhymes with Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tamihagglund.net/2015/05/speak.html&quot;&gt;Tami  Hagglund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/05/28/anon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/05/28/anon/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Self: Shut Up and Listen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had this long, self-deprecating diatribe written out, and decided to scrap it, because it was a bonafide s____y first draft, a la Anne Lamott. I went on and on about how astounding and outrageous it was (is!) that there are so many Christians out there defending the narrative given by abusers, rushing to “give grace” to them, and how I wanted nothing to do with those kinds of people. I ended with a small statement about letting victims have the platform and focus, which is exactly what I did NOT demonstrate in that first draft, OR in my conversations. This should NOT be about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth: I still want little to do with self-proclaiming Christians who defend abusers, and ignore the structures whence they came. (You can learn more about one of them at http://www.quiverfull.com, if you can tolerate a poorly designed website. Cross-refence with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patheos.com/blogs/nolongerquivering/what-is-quiverfull/&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth: I feel more like spewing curses these days than I ever have, due to feelings of anger at injustice. (See this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.carisadel.com/4009/christians-and-the-love-of-power/&quot;&gt;example.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I do want to be more proactive in stepping out of the way, instead of publishing a story centered around myself. I don’t want to further a toxic, unsafe environment for survivors by clinging to the microphone. I want to learn to listen. As such, I am shutting up about it now, and tomorrow will be publishing a piece written by a survivor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/05/27/dear-self-shut-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/05/27/dear-self-shut-up/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current-ish Reads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/roman wives.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roman Wives, Roman Widows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I could just point you to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/23284725-sabrina-peters&quot;&gt;Goodreads account&lt;/a&gt;, but that would be too easy, and not as fun as talking about my most recent reads. I’ll start with most current, and talk about some of the last few books I’ve read so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Roman-Wives-Widows-Appearance-Communities/dp/0802849717&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roman Wives, Roman Widows&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which I am finally wrapping up after beginning last year, is an incredible monograph by Bruce Winter, shedding historical and cultural light on some difficult Pauline passages that include instructions toward women (e.g.,1 Corinthians 11, Pastoral Epistles). It is really fascinating from a nerdy, historical point of view, although kind of dry (but not long!). Here’s a juicy quote that Winter shares from Musonius Rufus, courtesy of C. E. Lutz:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Women who associate with philosophers are bound to be arrogant for the most part and presumptuous, in that abandoning their own households and turning to the company of men they practice speeches, talk like sophists, and analyze syllogisms, when they ought to be sitting at home spinning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Gifts-Imperfection-Think-Supposed-Embrace-ebook/dp/B00BS03LL6/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1428595691&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=gifts+of+imperfection&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Gifts of Imperfection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the second book I’ve read by Brene´ Brown. It’s a good reminder to enjoy life and not worry about what others think, and an easy read. Recommended if you struggle with perfectionism, and worth more than one read. (Note: The Kindle version is currently $6.45!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Half-Yellow-Chimamanda-Ngozi-Adichie-ebook/dp/B001L83PLQ/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1428595867&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=half+of+a+yellow+sun&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half of a Yellow Sun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is by one of my favorite authors, Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie. It is a raw, human portrayal of love and family during the Nigerian Civil War in the late 1960s. This is the third book of hers I’ve read after &lt;a href=&quot;http://sabrinapeters.net/2014/06/09/americanah/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Americanah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Purple Hibiscus&lt;/em&gt;, and I recommend all of them. (Note: Do not waste your time on the film version of &lt;em&gt;Half of a Yellow Sun&lt;/em&gt;. It is one of the worst book-to-film adaptations I have seen in a while, and has little to offer as a film in of itself. Really disappointing.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman is an author I’ve recently discovered, that can hold me captive. He’s a great storyteller. I didn’t think I was so much of a fantasy or fairy-tales person (outside of Tolkien and Lewis) until I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Ocean-End-Lane-Novel/dp/0062255665&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean at the End of the Lane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was absolutely magical and completed within one day and three sittings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I was browsing Overdrive, saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/American-Gods-Neil-Gaiman/dp/0380789035/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1428596887&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=american+gods&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and thought, “why not?” Whoa. I felt like I needed a crash course review on mythology to keep up with the story’s significance (I was happy about the Kindle Wikipedia feature; it allowed me to view wiki entires without having to leave the application), but the writing is excellent. I was a bit put off by a few crassly detailed scenes, but I couldn’t let go of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it, guys. My goal is to read 52 books this year, so expect other posts like these ones; I can’t help but share about good books, and besides, as a librarian-in-training, you shouldn’t expect any less!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to know what books YOU’VE been reading - do share!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/04/09/books1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sabrinapeters.net/2015/04/09/books1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
